Hello, welcome everybody. How is everybody doing today? This is going to be an
大家好，欢迎各位。大家今天怎么样？这将是一堂
awesome listening and speaking class. I'm so glad that all of you are here. Welcome
非常棒的听说课。我很高兴大家都能来。欢迎
everybody. See the screen. All right. Now? Yes. Okay. So remember, good
各位。看到屏幕了吗？好的。现在呢？是的。好的。那么记住，良好
communication starts with good listening, being an active listener means showing
的沟通始于良好的倾听，做一个积极的倾听者意味着展现出
you're engaged. Sometimes we listen quickly for the main idea and that's our
你的专注。有时我们为了抓住大意会快速倾听，那是我们
fast and intuitive thinking and other times we need careful analytical
快速而直觉的思维方式；而另一些时候，我们需要仔细的、分析性的
listening and that's when we really kind of pick things apart and try to
倾听，那才是我们真正深入剖析事物并试图
understand the deeper meaning of those things. So we need to practice both types
理解其深层含义的时候。所以我们需要练习这两种倾听方式，
of listening to understand the superficial level of things in the meaning and
以便理解事物的表层含义
to understand (the) deeper analytical level of things. When you practice a lot, you get
和理解事物更深层次的分析性层面。当你练习多了，
the hang of it and you don't have to kind of deliberately seek to understand it
你就会掌握窍门，不必刻意去
so much. You'll just understand and it will become more intuitive with time but
努力理解那么多。你会自然而然地理解，并且随着时间的推移会变得更直观。但是
it's always good to analyze first. So we'll listen as the scenario is read
先进行分析总是好的。那么，我们来听一下这里朗读的场景。
here. I want you to listen to it twice with different focuses and I'm trying to
我希望你们带着不同的侧重点听两遍，我试图展示一些
show something that you might not understand. So don't feel bad if you don't. Okay.
你们可能不理解的东西。所以如果没听懂也不要难过。好的。
All right. Okay, team. For the new project, I need everyone to synergize their
好的。好的，各位同事。关于新项目，我需要每个人在周二下班前 (COB)
deliverables by COB Tuesday and ensure proactive stakeholder engagement. Make it
协同整合各自的交付成果，并确保积极主动地与利益相关者沟通。
snappy. Did you understand? The main idea, but there are some new words
请迅速处理。你理解了吗？大意明白了，但是有一些新词。
others are okay. Okay, so you have some experience which is great. You've got the
其他的还可以。好的，所以你有一些经验，这很好。你抓住了
main idea that we need to work together to get something done but there might
我们需要共同努力完成某事的大意，但这里可能有一些
be some things here that you don't understand. Which words are hard for you to
你不理解的地方。哪些词你觉得难以理解？
understand? So the words that I don't understand are
所以我不理解的词是
synergize and snappy. Okay, so to synergize something is basically to make
"synergize" 和 "snappy"。好的，那么 "synergize" 某事物基本上就是让事物
things in sync, right? When things are synchronized, they're synergized. They
同步，对吧？当事物同步时，它们就是 "synergized"（协同的）。它们
work well together, right? So we need everybody to basically come together and
能很好地协同工作、配合默契，对吧？所以我们需要每个人基本上都团结起来，
agree on what deliverables, what needs to be produced by Tuesday, and to make
就交付成果——即周二前需要产出的东西——达成一致，而 "make it snappy"
it snappy is to do it quickly. Oh, okay. When you're talking.
就是快速完成。哦，好的。当你在说话的时候，
You're using that word, right? Oh, make it snappy.
你用那个词，对吧？哦，“动作快点”(make it snappy)。
All right. So let's listen to a short scenario and imagine you're in this
好的。那么，让我们听一个简短的场景，想象你正在参加
this meeting. If you were to hear that in a meeting, what would you
这个会议。如果你在会议中听到那样的话，你会怎么做
do to interrupt to try to understand? If you had some sort of question, you have
来打断并试图理解？如果你有某种问题，你理解了大意，对吧？
the main idea, right? But you wouldn't probably want to listen to what comes next a
但你可能还是想听听接下来会说些什么。
little bit. How would you ask for clarification?
你会如何请求澄清呢？
Well, as you mentioned, everything is about listening. So I think I will wait the
嗯，正如您所说，一切都关乎倾听。所以我想我会等那个人
person to end what that person is (going to say)? And if I don't understand, then I will go
说完他（要说的话）？如果我不明白，那么我会去
and like, hey, I need clarification on this part of what I just say.
说，嘿，关于我刚才说的这部分，我需要澄清一下。
So you would wait for the person to finish saying what they want to say.* And that's because
所以你会等那个人说完他想说的话。*这是因为
you don't want to be rude or interrupt anyone when they're talking. Yes. Actually, I always
你不想在别人说话时显得无礼或打断他们。是的。实际上，我总是
tried to wait because you need to know what the person is thinking and not just to think like
尽量等待，因为你需要知道对方在想什么，而
that's what you're saying. So it's good not to make assumptions. I agree. And it's great to wait
不是只从字面意思去理解你所说的话。是的，不做假设是好的。我同意。而且等待
for those pauses in speech and conversation to know when we can ask for clarification.
谈话和对话中的那些停顿，以便知道何时可以请求澄清，这很好。
Okay. So how do we interrupt politely? That's part of what we're talking about today.
好的。那么我们如何礼貌地打断呢？这是我们今天讨论内容的一部分。
Asking for clarity. They're useful phrases. Well, I would say, excuse me,
请求澄清。有一些有用的短语。嗯，我会说，打扰一下，
what's like, that would be a good example.
比如，那会是一个很好的例子。
So I will say, excuse me, I just would like to know what you are trying to say when you are
所以我会说，打扰一下，我只是想知道当您谈论
talking about this contract or something like that. Okay. So I need more clarification on these
这份合同时，您想表达的是什么，或者类似这样的话。好的。所以我需要关于这些主题的更多澄清。
subjects. All right. It's very formal. I like that.
好的。非常正式。我喜欢这样。
Yes, we need to... that's like our environment when we talk with we have our meetings.
是的，我们需要……那就像我们开会时交谈的环境。
We can make* jokes outside, you know, but then we are with the meeting where we need to try to be
我们可以在外面开玩笑，你知道，但是当我们在开会时，我们需要努力做到
a really like professional. You can be more casual outside of the meeting, but in the meeting
非常专业。你可以在会议之外更随意一些，但在会议
itself, it's time to be professional and formal. All right. So this language register is really
本身，就应该表现得专业和正式。好的。所以这种语言风格确实
a bit formal and also intonation is important. You know, sounds rise and they fall too. So an
有点正式，而且语调也很重要。你知道，声音有起有落。所以
example would be sorry. Could you please repeat the part about COB or could you repeat the part
一个例子是，抱歉，您能重复一下关于 COB 的部分吗？或者，您能重复一下关于
about making it snappy? What does that mean? All right. So now notice that we use could here and could
“动作快点”(making it snappy) 的部分吗？那是什么意思？好的。现在注意我们这里用了 "could"，而 "could"
is considered more polite than can. So could is a little bit more formal and then can is a little
被认为比 "can" 更礼貌。所以 "could" 更正式一点，而 "can" 则
bit more casual, although you can use either one. Someone is not being disrespectful if they use can,
更随意一点，尽管两者都可以使用。如果有人用 "can"，并不代表他不尊重，
but if you want to show more formality, it's better to use could. Here's another example.
但如果你想表现得更正式，最好用 "could"。这里有另一个例子。
This time I would like for you to try to raise the intonation at the end. So is that right?
这次我希望你试着在结尾提高语调。比如，“是这样吗？”(Is that right?)
All right. Is that right? Can you, can you read this part here?
好的。“是这样吗？”你能，你能读一下这部分吗？
If I understand correctly, you're asking us to, is that right?
如果我理解正确的话，您是要求我们……，是这样吗？
Is that right? Yeah. And here's another example. We're working a lot. Is that right?
是这样吗？是的。这里还有另一个例子。我们工作很努力。是这样吗？
We have to come in this weekend. Is that right? All right. How about this one? Can you read
我们这个周末必须来。是这样吗？好的。这个怎么样？你能为我们读一下
this one for us? Could you please explain what you mean by snappy?
这个吗？您能解释一下您说的 "snappy" 是什么意思吗？
Uh-huh. Very good. Hi, snappy. Well, snappy means it should be different.
嗯哼。非常好。嗨，"snappy"。嗯，"snappy" 的意思是动作敏捷/干脆利落。
Well, no, I think that's fine. We can use, for example, like the one you said COB because
嗯，不，我觉得那样可以。我们可以用，例如，像您说的 COB，因为
there are some people* that don't know what COB means. You could just simply ask, could you
有些人不知道 COB 是什么意思。你可以简单地问，您能告诉我
tell me what snappy means? I don't know this. It's a new word for me, you could say.
"snappy" 是什么意思吗？我不认识这个词。这对我来说是个新词，你可以这么说。
You know, I think sometimes we feel embarrassed when we don't know something.
你知道，我想有时候当我们不知道某件事时，会感到尴尬。
And so we don't want to ask, we don't want to admit, but it's okay to clarify.
所以我们不想问，不想承认，但是请求澄清是可以的。
The whole purpose of communication and business is to understand and be understood.
沟通和商业的全部目的就是理解和被理解。
And a key takeaway from this slide here is basically we use could to make polite requests.
这张幻灯片的一个关键点基本上是，我们用 "could" 来提出礼貌的请求。
You can use discourse markers like excuse me or if I understand correctly you're asking
你可以使用像 "Excuse me" 或 "If I understand correctly, you're asking..." 或 "you're telling us that's right" 这样的话语标记，
or you're telling us that's right and then rephrasing what they say. Those are really great ways to
然后重述他们所说的话。这些都是非常好的方式
ask for clarification. All right. So go ahead, I'm sorry.
来请求澄清。好的。那么，请继续，抱歉。
No, maybe before I didn't use to do that, but now like I feel more confident to ask for
不，也许以前我不会那样做，但现在我感觉更有信心去询问词语的意思，
the meaning of the word, to (know) what they're saying. So we know what they're exactly there trying
去了解他们在说什么。所以我们知道他们到底想表达什么。
to communicate. Yeah... it only gets better with time.
是的……只会随着时间的推移越来越好。